<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poems | Emily Cibelli</title>
    <link>/poem/</link>
      <atom:link href="/poem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Poems</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Poems</title>
      <link>/poem/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/poem/poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/poem/poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ballad-of-marco-polo&#34;&gt;The Ballad of Marco Polo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stephen Vincent Benét&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across this poem in a 10th grade literary anthology (possibly 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books/about/Book_of_Poetry_1.html?id=IWU1FdGqXBIC&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;
?) At the time, I was in the short-lived habit of typing up poems I liked, so this one got saved to my old family computer, along with a few other favorites. I found it a few years later and was equally charmed, and looked it up to see what other information I could gather. But despite SVB&amp;rsquo;s significant legacy, the poem itself is barely documented anywhere online - at the moment, just a handful of citations referencing the original issue of the Atlantic Monthly in which it was published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no literary academic, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t had luck finding any scholarly traces of it either; in fact, it didn&amp;rsquo;t even appear in any of the Benét anthologies I&amp;rsquo;ve looked through. I&amp;rsquo;m reproducing it here because I&amp;rsquo;m utterly fond of it - probably more so because I&amp;rsquo;ve constructed a bit of a mystery in my head about its lack of notoriety - and feel it should have a bit more attention and web presence. If you know something about the poem, or enjoyed it as much as I do, please be in touch. (I hear from about one person a year, and it&amp;rsquo;s a treat!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marco Polo, curious man,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;What drove you to seek that Kublai Khan?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it was youth, for I was young,&lt;br&gt;
Perhaps it was my father&amp;rsquo;s tongue&lt;br&gt;
The desert hawk I had never seen&lt;br&gt;
Till the years of my age were turned fifteen,&lt;br&gt;
For I was not born when he went away&lt;br&gt;
To trade beyond the rim of day,&lt;br&gt;
And, when he returned, we were strange and shy,&lt;br&gt;
Meeting each other, he and I,&lt;br&gt;
For a lost bride&amp;rsquo;s eyes looked out at him,&lt;br&gt;
My mother&amp;rsquo;s, who died in bearing me,&lt;br&gt;
And the lines of his visage were great and grim&lt;br&gt;
And I knew he had been in Tartary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marco Polo, how did it fall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;That at last you followed him, after all?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the world shut in with candlelight,&lt;br&gt;
They would talk to each other, night on night,&lt;br&gt;
While the water lapped at the landing stair&lt;br&gt;
And they hardly knew that I was there&lt;br&gt;
Except as a shadow the candle threw&lt;br&gt;
When the wind before the morning blew&lt;br&gt;
And the great house creaked like a ship of stone,&lt;br&gt;
Maffeo and Nicolo,&lt;br&gt;
Talking of marvels past reknown,&lt;br&gt;
Talking of wonders still to do -&lt;br&gt;
Their talk was honey and wine and snow&lt;br&gt;
How could I help but drink it down?&lt;br&gt;
How could I help but thirst and burn,&lt;br&gt;
When the opened the bag of camel&amp;rsquo;s hair&lt;br&gt;
And looked at the marvel hidden there&lt;br&gt;
And said, &amp;ldquo;It is time and we must return?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marco Polo, what did you see,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When at length you came to Tartary?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I have been where I have been,&lt;br&gt;
But how can I tell you what I have seen?&lt;br&gt;
I know the desert of the dry tree&lt;br&gt;
Whose branches bear eternity,&lt;br&gt;
And the hot sickness of the noon.&lt;br&gt;
I drank the mare&amp;rsquo;s milk of the tents,&lt;br&gt;
I saw the musk ox gape at me,&lt;br&gt;
I have had gold and frankincense&lt;br&gt;
And silks that glitter like the moon,&lt;br&gt;
But what can I tell you that will make you see?&lt;br&gt;
Marco Polo, wandering sword&lt;br&gt;
What manner of man did you call lord?&lt;br&gt;
I have been the pope&amp;rsquo;s and doge&amp;rsquo;s man,&lt;br&gt;
But I never knew master like Kublai Khan.&lt;br&gt;
The sons of his body sit ten by ten&lt;br&gt;
At buffets of precious napery,&lt;br&gt;
When he hunts, he hunts with ten thousand men&lt;br&gt;
And his Tartar falcons darken the sky,&lt;br&gt;
He has jewels uncounted and golden plate&lt;br&gt;
Whence even his meanest slaves may eat,&lt;br&gt;
And he sits and numbers the hairs of fate&lt;br&gt;
With a great, tame lion crouched at his feet,&lt;br&gt;
And his mercy as fair as a white ram&amp;rsquo;s fleece,&lt;br&gt;
Mighty in battle and just in peace,&lt;br&gt;
Star of the city of Kanbalu,&lt;br&gt;
Khan of Khans and Great of the Great&lt;br&gt;
Whose bounty falls like the morning dew -&lt;br&gt;
Since Adam delved and Eve span&lt;br&gt;
Who ever saw a prince like Kublai Khan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marco Polo, tell me how&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Your Venice talks of your travels now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They call me braggart, they call me liar,&lt;br&gt;
They gawk at me like an eater of fire,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lsquo;Millions&amp;rsquo; Polo, the fable-monger,&lt;br&gt;
Such being his custom in Cathay.&lt;br&gt;
But they laughed with their beards another way,&lt;br&gt;
When we came back in &amp;lsquo;95&lt;br&gt;
Like ghosts returned to a world alive,&lt;br&gt;
With our gear still smelling of musk and civet&lt;br&gt;
And my father&amp;rsquo;s beard grown whiter than privet,&lt;br&gt;
Two old men and a younger one&lt;br&gt;
Who had looked in the eye of the Eastern sun.&lt;br&gt;
And lived - and lived to tell the tale&lt;br&gt;
Which I tell to the shadows in this, my jail.&lt;br&gt;
Why, my very cousins did not own us&lt;br&gt;
And the jeering crowd was ready to stone us&lt;br&gt;
Till we ripped the riches out of our rags&lt;br&gt;
And proved we were Polos - by moneybags!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let them laugh as long as they like today!&lt;br&gt;
I have seen Cathay, I have seen Cathay!&lt;br&gt;
Their little Europe - their dwarfish West -&lt;br&gt;
Their doge with his ring and marriage fee!&lt;br&gt;
I have stolen the eggs from the phoenix nest&lt;br&gt;
And walked by the shores of the Ocean-Sea,&lt;br&gt;
The earth-encircler, the Asian main,&lt;br&gt;
And, if Kublai lived, I would go again,&lt;br&gt;
For what is their quarrel of gimcrack lords,&lt;br&gt;
Their toy fleets sailing a herring pond,&lt;br&gt;
By the might that mastered the Tartar hordes?&lt;br&gt;
There are worlds beyond, there are worlds beyond,&lt;br&gt;
Worlds to be conquered, worlds to be found,&lt;br&gt;
By river and desert and burning ground,&lt;br&gt;
Even, perchance, by the Ocean-Sea,&lt;br&gt;
If a man has courage enough to dare,&lt;br&gt;
And I know that others will follow me&lt;br&gt;
And I mark the roads that will take them there,&lt;br&gt;
The roads of the golden caravan,&lt;br&gt;
The whole great East in its roaring youth,&lt;br&gt;
For - there was a prince named Kublai Khan -&lt;br&gt;
And I, the liar, have told the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
